Supun Nakandala

Phone: (+1) 812-558-6888 3232 EBU3B CSE Email: snakanda@eng.ucsd.edu 9500 Gilman Drive Web: scnakandala.github.io La Jolla, CA 92093

Research Interests My research interest lies broadly in the intersection of ML and Systems, an emerging area which is increasingly referred to as ML Systems. My current research work involves implementing data management inspired abstractions, algorithms, and systems, for improving the efficiency and usability of Deep Learning powered ML workloads.

Education

University of California, San Diego, CA

Sept 2017 - Present

PhD, Computer Science. GPA: 4.0/4.0

Thesis Advisor: Arun Kumar

University of Moratuwa, Sri Lanka

Aug 2010 - April 2015

Bachelor of the Science of Engineering, Computer Science & Engineering.

GPA: 4.11/4.20.

Publications

Krypton: Accelerating Occlusion based Deep CNN Explainability Workloads

Nakandala, S., Kumar, A., Papakonstantinou, Y.

(Under Submission).

Materialization Trade-offs for Feature Transfer from Deep CNNs for Multimodal Data Analytics

Nakandala, S., Kumar, A.

(Under Submission).

Gendered Conversation in a Social Game-Streaming Platform

Nakandala, S., Giovanni, C., Norman, S., Ahn, Y.

In Proceedings of 11th International AAAI Conference On Web And Social Media (ICWSM) 2017.

Apache Airavata Security Manager: Authentication and Authorization Implementations for a Multi-Tenant eScience Framework

Nakandala, S., Gunasinghe, H., Marru, S., Pierce, M.

In Proceedings of IEEE 12^{th} International Conference on e-Science 2016.

Anatomy of the SEAGrid Science Gateway

Nakandala, S., Pamidighantam, S., Yodage, S., Doshi, N., Abeysinghe, E., Kankanamalage, C.P., Marru, S. and Pierce, M.

In Proceedings of Extreme Science & Engineering Discovery Environments Conference (XSEDE) on Diversity, Big Data, and Science at Scale 2016.

Current Projects

Cerebro: The goal of this project is to make the end-to-end model selection process more efficient when developing ML models. To this end, we are developing a new system which takes inspirations from RDBMS, scalable distributed systems, and operations research literature.

Medical Data to Knowledge: In this project, which is done in collaboration with researchers from the UCSD Dept. of Public Health, I develop new ML models to predict the sitting patterns for a large cohort of human subjects belonging to different age groups using data from hip worn accelerometers. The predicted results will then be used to better understand the relationship between human sitting patterns and metabolic health.

Experience

Research Software Developer

Oct 2015 - Aug 2017

Indiana University

Worked as a developer for the Apache Airavata project, which is a science gateway
middleware framework to enable users to compose, manage, execute, and monitor
large scale applications and workflows on distributed computing resources such as local
clusters, supercomputers, computational grids, and computing clouds.

Group Website: https://sgrc.iu.edu

Google Summer of Code Intern

May 2014 - Sept 2014

Apache Airavata

• Implemented API security capabilities for the Airavata Thrift services for the communication between end-user gateways and the Airavata server.

Link: https://goo.gl/4qAS3X)

Google Summer of Code Intern phpMyAdmin

May 2013 - Sept 2013

 \bullet Refactored the SQL executor and column structure manipulation code in phpMyAdmin, which is an open-source web based interface for MySQL databases

Link: https://goo.gl/JNk3vM

Awards

IBM Gold Medal for the Best Academic Performance in Computer Science & Engineering - University of Moratuwa 2015

Mahapola Higher Education Merit Scholarship for Undergraduate Studies - Government of Sri Lanka 2010

Posters

Materialization Trade-offs for Feature Transfer from Deep CNNs for Multimodal Data Analytics
SysML Conference, SoCal DB Day
2018

Talks

Materialization Trade-offs for Feature Transfer from Deep CNNs for Multimodal Data Analytics
UCSD CNS Research Review, UCSD Database Seminar 2018

References

Arun Kumar

Assistant Professor, University of California, San Diego arunkk@eng.ucsd.edu

Yong-Yeol Ahn Associate Professor, Indiana University Bloomington yyahn@iu.edu

Marlon Pierce

Director - Science Gateways Research Center, Indiana University Bloomington marpierc@iu.edu